[
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following security goals were present for the WEP design:",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "To be equivalent to the Kerberos access policy.",
      "To be equivalent to wired access point security.",
      "To be equivalent to wide ethernet protocol.",
      "To be equivalent to wireless entity policy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which key distribution protocol is specified in WEP?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Diffie-Hellman key distribution.",
      "RC4 key distribution.",
      "RSA key distribution.",
      "There is no specified key distribution protocol in WEP."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the major weakness in WEP, exploited by the PTW attack used in the lab?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "RC4 is broken even with 104 bit keys",
      "The initialization vector is too short",
      "No protection against message replay",
      "The integrity check value is too short"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "WPA and WPA2 share the following security component:",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["CCMP", "TKIP", "AES", "RC4"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many message integrity failures have to be logged in order the Temporal Key Integrity Protocol to start the Denial Of Service mechanism:",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Two failures within 60 seconds",
      "Two failures within 30 seconds",
      "Two failures within 10 seconds",
      "Two failures within 1 second"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In RSN, the encryption and message authentication are realized via",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["AES-GCM", "AES-CBC", "AES-HMAC", "AES-CCMP"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How big is the message integrity code in RSN",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["32 bits", "48 bits", "64 bits", "128 bits\n2"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Extensible Authentication Protocol (EAP)?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for upper-layer authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for physical layer authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for PKI authentication methods",
      "EAP is a set of encapsulation messages for RADIUS server authentication methods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In GSM, what is the role of the Visitor Location Register:",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "When mobile equipment register to the network, to retrieve the information for that equipment from HLR.",
      "To protect the anonymity of the owner of the mobile equipment.",
      "To obtain a session key from HLR.",
      "To communicate the user’s Authentication Center (AuC)."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which security mechanism is NOT present in GSM:",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Authentication",
      "Confidentiality",
      "Anonymity",
      "Authorization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In GSM, what is the role of A8 algorithm:",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "For production of random numbers",
      "For encryption key generation",
      "For user authentication",
      "For Data encryption"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The function f6( ) in the MAPsec protocol of UMTS is:",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "AES in counter mode",
      "AES in CBC mode",
      "KASUMI in counter mode",
      "KASUMI in CBC mode"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many modes of protection offers MAPsec?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the crucial protocol in IP Multimedia Subsystem",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Internet Key Exchange (IKE)",
      "MAPsec",
      "Session Initiation Protocol (SIP)",
      "IPsec\n3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A simple description of MILENAGE functions can be done as:",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "<math><msub><mi>f</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi>,<mi>K</mi></mrow></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>))</mo></math>; where <math><mi>i</mi><mo>=</mo>1,2,3,4,5</math>, and <math><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math> are distinct constants",
      "<math><msub><mi>f</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi>,<mi>K</mi></mrow></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2295;</mo><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>)</mo></math>; where <math><mi>i</mi><mo>=</mo>1,2,3,4,5</math>, and <math><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math> are distinct constants",
      "<math><msub><mi>f</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi>,<mi>K</mi></mrow></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo></math>; where <math><mi>i</mi><mo>=</mo>1,2,3,4,5</math>, and <math><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math> are distinct constants",
      "<math><msub><mi>f</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi>,<mi>K</mi></mrow></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>E</mi><mi>K</mi></msub><mo>(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2295;</mo><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math>; where <math><mi>i</mi><mo>=</mo>1,2,3,4,5</math>, and <math><msub><mi>c</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></math> are distinct constants"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two ciphers are used in UEA1 and UEA2",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "AES and KASUMI",
      "AES and RC4",
      "AES and SNOW 3G",
      "KASUMI and SNOW 3G"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In UMTS, the function f9( ) is used for:",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Integrity key generation",
      "Integrity protection",
      "Encryption key generation",
      "Encryption"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is encryption located in the UMTS stack of protocols?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "In Physical Layer and Media Access Control Layer",
      "In Media Access Control Layer and Radio Link Control Layer",
      "In Radio Link Control Layer and Radio Resource Control Protocol",
      "In Radio Resource Control Protocol and Higher Layers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In UMTS, the security mechanisms employed between the Mobile Station and the Radio\nNetwork Controller are responsible for:",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Sequence Number Management",
      "Encryption and Integrity Protection",
      "User Authentication",
      "Network Authentication"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In LTE, the Home Subscriber Server has the following information:",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "policy control and decision-making rules,",
      "IP address allocation for the UE,",
      "buffer of downlink data while the MME paging,",
      "information about the PDNs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In LTE, E-UTRAN is the part of the whole system infrastructure responsible for the:",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "radio access network",
      "circuit switch core network",
      "packet switch core network",
      "evolved packet core network\n4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many security levels has LTE?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["5", "4", "3", "2"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The following component IS NOT a part of the RFID technology",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Transceiver – Tag Reader",
      "Transponder – RFID tag",
      "Antenna",
      "Infra Red Analog/Digital Converter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The EPCGen2 tag is",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "A passive tag that allows just low-speed reading and sortation",
      "An Active tag that allows high-speed reading and sortation",
      "A passive tag that allows high-speed reading and sortation",
      "An Active tag that allows just low-speed reading and sortation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In RFID, the usual budget for implementation of the cryptographic primitives is:",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "100 – 200 gates",
      "200 – 500 gates",
      "500 – 1000 gates",
      "200 – 2000 gates"
    ]
  }
]
